ALEXANDER SURIYUTH

+1 (613) 484-4464alec.suriyuth@gmail.comalecsuriyuth.ca

Recent **engineering graduate** and competitive cyclist with a desire for personal growth and to develop **impactful projects** focusing on **creativity** and **sustainability**.

highlights:

Analyzed the feasibility, design and integration of daylighting systems into the Carleton University High Performance Building Multidisciplinary Capstone Project.

Worked within and managed the front-of-house service team of The Cyclery to ensure that the appropriate solutions for customer needs were identified and executed while deadlines were met successfully.

▶ Brand ambassador

representing *Knolly Bikes* and *The Cyclery* in eastern Canada/USA through community engagement, commitment to racing and regular media contributions.

education:

Carleton University:

Bachelor of Engineering: Sustainable and Renewable Energy w/ minor: Business for Engineers.

2013 - 2018

work experience:

Terrasculpt Inc.

Nov. - Dec. 2018 Mont Ste. Marie QC

General Labourer

 Used and maintained small engine tools (chainsaws, leaf blowers, and brush cutters) and mini-excavator (Kubota U17) to support the development of new mountain biking trails and ski runs at Mont Ste. Marie ski hill.

The Cyclery

2016 - 2018 Ottawa ON

Front Service Technician and Manager

- Organized workflow and delegated front service tasks to meet deadlines.
- Worked in a team environment to identify and execute appropriate solutions for customer's needs.
- Assembled and serviced primarily high end bicycles, including race bikes for local and national level athletes.

J&J Cycle

2011 - 2016 Kingston ON

Salesperson and Mechanic

- Determined customer needs and provided the appropriate response to promote sales and improve customer satisfaction.
- Assembled and maintained entry and mid-range hybrids and mountain bikes.

Alec Suriyuth

2011 - 2014 Kingston ON

Independent Videographer

- Collaborated with local businesses to showcase and generate public awareness of their products and services.
- Past clients: Kingston Water Access Group/City of Kingston, Unovelo Bicycles, Sanger's Shotcrete and Westbrook Golf Club.

applied projects:

alecsuriyuth.ca

2018 - Present [Link]

- Ongoing development of a personal web space to showcase and promote my brand and experiences.
- Programs used: Github (hosting), Cloudflare (SSL services) and Brackets (development).

Northern Nomad Tiny Home

2017

[Link]

 Assisted in construction related activities for the Carleton University Northern Nomad tiny home including blower door testing and interior finishing.

applied projects continued:

Capstone Project: High Performance Building 2016 - 2017

2016 - 2017 [Link]

- Led a team of seven students to design and integrate innovative power generation and smart building systems into the project based on the ZIBI development in Ottawa ON.
- Utilized DIALux to analyze the feasibility and use of daylighting systems (light shelves, light pipes, a unique false ceiling design) to improve occupant health and productivity in order to meet LEED certification criteria.
- Integration with the large, multidisciplinary team was a primary focus of the project.

Term Project: Brigid's Well Pub Marketing Plan 2017

- Developed and presented a marketing plan based on Brigid's Well Pub.
- Market research, segmentation and situational analysis was completed and strategic recommendations were developed.

Term Project: Net-Zero Townhouse 2016

- Worked with a small multidisciplinary team to design a net-zero townhouse using SketchUp and HOT2000.
- Considered onsite renewable power generation, HVAC, lighting, and building envelope during design.
- Calculated energy load to size an appropriate HVAC system.

Term Project: Small Scale Hydrokinetic Power Plant 2016

Designed a hydroelectric power plant for Fort Liard, NWT utilizing the Mackenzie River.

• Climate and geotechnical data was used to determine feasibility and outline project restrictions.

• Utilized Creo Parametric and QBlade to design and 3D print the body of a scaled hydrokinetic turbine for testing in the Carleton University wind tunnel.

skills:

Technical:

- Working knowledge of Creo Parametric, QBlade, DIALux, Matlab, Excel, Word, and VSCO.
- Applied engineering theory to solve thermodynamics, heat transfer and fluid machinery problems.
- Experienced and knowledgeable in complete bicycle assembly and component servicing.
- Knowledgeable in HTML and CSS coding.

Leadership:

- Led project groups to complete deliverables on time and to meet specified requirements.
- Experienced utilizing the diversity of a team as a strength to improve overall team performance.
- Expressed the leadership qualities and community involvement representative of a successful brand ambassador.

extra-curricular activities/interests:

Athlete: Enduro Mountain Biking

- Commitment to year round to training, health and high level competition.
- 2018 Enduro World Series Global Ranking: 324th.
- Supported by D.I.Y. MTB and Knolly Bikes.
- Return on investment to sponsors and support in the form of community involvement and media production.
- Media published on Pinkbike.com.

Photography

[Link]

- A primarily self-growth focused project to expand technical and storytelling abilities with the goal to create thoughtprovoking and impactful photographs.
- Commercial contributions for Bombtrack Bicycle Company, Knolly Bikes and Kitsbow Apparel.